<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  AppStream metainfo for Omnizen Desktop.

  Read by GNOME Software, KDE Discover, and other Linux app stores to
  show name, license, description, screenshots, and bug-tracker links.
  Without this file the .deb / .rpm / .AppImage shows up as "Unknown
  license" with no description.

  Installed inside the .deb at /usr/share/metainfo/com.omnizen.desktop.metainfo.xml
  via electron-builder.yml's linux.extraResources block.

  Spec: https://www.freedesktop.org/software/appstream/docs/sect-Metadata-Application.html
-->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.omnizen.desktop</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.omnizen.desktop.desktop</launchable>

  <name>Omnizen</name>
  <summary>Native chat app routing every frontier model through your Omnizen plan</summary>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <developer id="ai.omnizen">
    <name>Anchorblock Venture Capital</name>
  </developer>

  <description>
    <p>
      Omnizen Desktop is a fork of Open WebUI Desktop, pre-wired to your
      Omnizen subscription. Chat history and uploaded files stay on your
      machine; every chat completion routes through api.omnizen.ai so
      one key powers every frontier model.
    </p>
    <p>Highlights:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>One sign-in, every frontier model - OpenAI, Anthropic, Gemini, DeepSeek and more, on your single Omnizen plan.</li>
      <li>Local data - chat history and uploads stay on your computer, not on a hosted multi-tenant database.</li>
      <li>System-wide Spotlight + voice input.</li>
      <li>Auto-updates from the Omnizen release feed.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Early alpha. Builds are unsigned for now; macOS Gatekeeper and
      Windows SmartScreen will warn on first launch. See the README for
      bypass instructions.
    </p>
  </description>

  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>Chat</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>chat</keyword>
    <keyword>ai</keyword>
    <keyword>llm</keyword>
    <keyword>openai</keyword>
    <keyword>claude</keyword>
    <keyword>omnizen</keyword>
    <keyword>openwebui</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <url type="homepage">https://omnizen.ai</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/anchorblock/desktop/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://omnizen.ai/docs</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/anchorblock/desktop</url>
  <url type="contribute">https://github.com/anchorblock/desktop/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md</url>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <recommends>
    <display_length compare="ge">medium</display_length>
    <internet>always</internet>
  </recommends>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="0.0.35" date="2026-05-23">
      <description>
        <p>Directly wire the chat window when the local server is ready and Omnizen is the default connection. Reactive $effect bypasses every event-ordering race (connection:open lost, omnizen:signed-in not fired, auto-connect timing) and just shows the webview as soon as $serverInfo.reachable flips true. The welcome card with the Omnizen sign-in CTA only shows when the user is genuinely not signed in or the server hasn't started.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.34" date="2026-05-23">
      <description>
        <p>Fix the auto-connect blank-screen on subsequent .desktop launches. Two races closed: (1) the OpenWebUI silent-bootstrap now completes BEFORE SERVER_REACHABLE flips true, so the webview's preload never reads a null JWT and OpenWebUI never bounces to /auth; (2) main now caches the latest connection:open and replays it when the renderer signals it has mounted, so a slow first paint can't strand the user at view='welcome'.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.33" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Fix the post-sign-in blank screen. The welcome view's OmnizenSignIn card collapses when sign-in completes, leaving an empty welcome background visible because view-state never transitioned to 'connected'. Backend was fully working - chat was loaded, models populated - just not visible. Now both the welcome card and the persistent banner dispatch an 'omnizen:signed-in' event that Connections.svelte listens for to auto-connect to the local server and switch to the connected view immediately.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.32" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>One-line fix to the v0.0.31 silent bootstrap. OpenWebUI 0.9.5's signup endpoint rejects `omnizen-desktop@local` as invalid email format (pydantic EmailStr won't accept `.local`). Bootstrap got HTTP 400 silently and users still saw the manual signup form. Now uses `omnizen-desktop@example.com` (RFC 2606 reserved TLD) which OpenWebUI accepts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.31" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Silent OpenWebUI sign-in. The desktop now bootstraps a hidden local admin on first launch, persists the credentials in safeStorage, and injects the session JWT into the webview's localStorage via the preload script before any OpenWebUI page script runs. Users never see OpenWebUI's login or signup form - the Omnizen device-flow they completed in their browser is the only sign-in. Reverts the v0.0.30 ENABLE_SIGNUP workaround.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.30" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>OpenWebUI 0.9.5's WEBUI_AUTH=False mode is half-broken (config reports auth disabled but /openai/models still 401s "Not authenticated" because the auto-login never completes inside the webview storage partition). Reverts to default auth + sets ENABLE_SIGNUP=true so the user can create the local admin once on first launch. Two-step on first run (Omnizen sign-in + local OpenWebUI signup) but it actually loads the model list afterwards.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.29" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes ERR_CONNECTION_REFUSED after sign-in. The 2.5 s static wait before reloading the webview wasn't enough for the local OpenWebUI to restart (it takes 6-10 s on first run). Now we poll the local URL until it accepts connections, then reload. Also hides the 'Open in Browser' fallback for localhost connections - opening the bundled server in a separate browser doesn't help.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.28" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Sets WEBUI_AUTH=False on the bundled OpenWebUI so users aren't blocked behind a second local login screen after signing in with Omnizen. The desktop is single-user; Omnizen sign-in is the only auth boundary that matters. Without this, users hit a login form with no way to create an account because OpenWebUI's default ENABLE_SIGNUP is false.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.27" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Onboarding fix: sign-in is now a centered full-area welcome card on first launch (was a thin top banner that left the broken chat view visible underneath). After successful sign-in the active webview reloads against the freshly-restarted local server so the chat shows Omnizen-routed models immediately - no manual refresh required.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.26" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Linux: fixes the menu/icon visibility - the auto-generated .desktop file was invalid because the multi-line description leaked into the Comment field, so GNOME never indexed the app. Replaces with an explicit single-line Comment plus Categories, Keywords, and a multi-size icon ladder (16, 24, 32, 48, 64, 128, 256, 512, 1024 px) so menu launchers can render at small sizes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.25" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Onboarding + brand polish: Omnizen sign-in is now the primary first-launch CTA (no more "select a connection" dead-end), the embedded chat surface brands as Omnizen via WEBUI_NAME, and em-dashes are stripped from UI strings.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.24" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Drops the Flatpak build target - the electronjs BaseApp cache was racing on the GitHub Linux x64 runner and stranding the otherwise-successful .deb / .AppImage / .snap uploads. AppImage covers the same use case.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.23" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes the v0.0.22 build pipeline (an invalid electron-builder config field blocked all platforms). Adds AppStream metainfo so GNOME Software / KDE Discover render the package metadata correctly, plus macOS Info.plist + Windows installer metadata.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.21" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>First full-matrix alpha - Linux ARM64 builds now ship alongside x64. Drops phantomjs-prebuilt transitive dependency that was blocking npm ci on arm64 runners.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.20" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Initial alpha. Persistent Omnizen sign-in banner above the chat webview, dev-mode DevTools docked, Wayland shortcut-failure toasts silenced, V8 Turbofan renderer crash mitigated.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
